<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mediation in the Ninth Circuit on United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit</title>
    <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mediation in the Ninth Circuit on United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bob Kaiser&lt;span style=&#39;font-weight: normal;&#39;&gt;, Circuit Mediator&lt;/span&gt;</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/bob-kaiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/bob-kaiser/</guid>
      <description>Prior to joining the Ninth Circuit mediation office, Bob mediated federal cases as a Circuit Mediator for the Sixth Circuit Court Appeals and also as a mediator for the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of Ohio. Bob has also mediated hundreds of cases as a private mediator. Before devoting his full-time efforts to mediation, Bob practiced law for 20 years, litigating and trying a wide variety of civil cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chris Goelz&lt;span style=&#39;font-weight: normal;&#39;&gt;, Circuit Mediator&lt;/span&gt;</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/chris-goelz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/chris-goelz/</guid>
      <description>Chris has been a Circuit Mediator for the Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals for 30 years. Before joining the court&amp;rsquo;s mediation office, he was a Motions Attorney for the Ninth Circuit. Prior to coming to the court Chris was a civil litigator in a small San Francisco firm. Chris has taught negotiation as an Adjunct Professor at the University of Washington School of Law and is an author of a Ninth Circuit practice guide published by the Rutter Group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Information</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/contact-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/contact-information/</guid>
      <description>Circuit Mediation Office E-mail:    ca09_mediation@ca9.uscourts.gov
   San Francisco Office:  Circuit Mediation Office
Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals
James R. Browning Courthouse
95 Seventh Street
P.O. Box 193939
San Francisco, California 94119-3939(415) 355-7900 (main line)
(415) 355-8566 (fax)   Seattle Office:  Circuit Mediation Office
Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals
William K. Nakamura Courthouse
1010 Fifth Avenue
Seattle, Washington 98104-1104
(206) 224-2320 (main line)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/frequently-asked-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/frequently-asked-questions/</guid>
      <description>The Mediation Questionnaire What is the Mediation Questionnaire?
 The Mediation Questionnaire (&amp;ldquo;MQ&amp;rdquo;) is a fillable form that provides information relevant to the suitability of the appeal for mediation. Appellants are required to file an MQ within 7 days of docketing the appeal. See Ninth Circuit Rules 3-4 and 15-2. Once it has been submitted, all parties will receive an NDA that has a link that will enable parties to submit relevant confidential information directly to the Circuit Mediators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jonathan Westen&lt;span style=&#39;font-weight: normal;&#39;&gt;, Circuit Mediator&lt;/span&gt;</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/jonathan-westen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/jonathan-westen/</guid>
      <description>Prior to joining the mediation office, Jonathan served as a Supervising Staff Attorney for the Ninth Circuit. Before joining the court, Jonathan was a litigator at a national law firm in San Francisco. Jonathan serves as a volunteer panel mediator for the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of California. Jonathan went to Berkeley Law School and then clerked for Judge Bruce Black and Chief Judge Parker on the Federal District Court of New Mexico.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyungah &amp;ldquo;Kay&amp;rdquo; Suk&lt;span style=&#39;font-weight: normal;&#39;&gt;, Circuit Mediator&lt;/span&gt;</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/kay-suk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/kay-suk/</guid>
      <description>Before joining the court, Kay was a mediator in private practice, a member of the American Arbitration Association and an Attorney Mediator with the California Department of Fair Employment and Housing.&amp;nbsp; Prior to focusing full-time on mediation, Kay was a Deputy Attorney General with the California Department of Justice as a civil litigator and an Administrative Law Judge with the California Office of Administrative Hearings.&amp;nbsp; Raised in the San Francisco Bay Area, Kay received her J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for Mediation</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/preparing-for-mediation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/preparing-for-mediation/</guid>
      <description>The most successful mediations are typically those in which both counsel and their clients are fully prepared. Thorough preparation means understanding both the legal and the practical dimensions of the dispute. Counsel will want to make sure that they understand the relevant law and facts, know the standard of review on appeal, and that they have considered how the appeal, and the litigation itself, serves the client’s larger goals.  Legal analysis alone may be only one part of the equation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relevant Rules, Forms, and Orders</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/relevant-rules-forms-and-orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/relevant-rules-forms-and-orders/</guid>
      <description>Relevant Rules and Forms   Federal Rule of Appellate Procedure 33: Appeal Conferences   Circuit Rule 33-1: Settlement Programs – Appeal Conferences   Ninth Circuit General Order 7.3: Cases Subject to Mediation   Circuit Rule 3-4: Mediation Questionnaire   Circuit Rule 15-2: Mediation Questionnaire in Agency Cases   Mediation Questionnaire Form   Sample Motions and Orders   Sample Motion to Dismiss   Sample Stipulated Motion to Dismiss Voluntarily F.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/resources/</guid>
      <description>Questions to Consider When Preparing for Mediation   Mediation works best when all participants know what really matters to them. What are the key needs and interests of yours that, if satisfied, would allow you to resolve this matter? Key needs or interests could be, for example, certainty, closure, economic security, avoidance of legal precedent, avoidance of future litigation, fairness, respect, understanding or institutional change.   What are the key interests of the other parties to the dispute?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roxane Ashe&lt;span style=&#39;font-weight: normal;&#39;&gt;, Circuit Mediator&lt;/span&gt;</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/roxane-ashe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/roxane-ashe/</guid>
      <description>Roxane has been a Circuit Mediator for Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals since 1998 and has mediated over two thousand appellate cases. Roxane is also the principal mediator for employment matters brought under the Circuit&#39;s Employment Dispute Resolution Plan and serves as a panel mediator for the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of California. Prior to joining the court&amp;rsquo;s mediation office, Roxane was Supervising Ninth Circuit Motions Attorney, Assistant Circuit Executive for Legal Affairs, and practiced civil litigation at a large firm in St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Motions and Orders</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/sample-motions-and-orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/sample-motions-and-orders/</guid>
      <description>If the parties settle the case, the Circuit Mediator will work with them to ensure that the proper documentation dismissing the appeal is filed with the court. If the parties are unable to resolve their appeal, the matter will be released from the Mediation Program and the mediator will ensure that all procedural matters, such as briefing schedules, etc., have been taken care of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sasha M. Cummings&lt;span style=&#39;font-weight: normal;&#39;&gt;, Circuit Mediator&lt;/span&gt;</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/sasha-m-cummings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/sasha-m-cummings/</guid>
      <description>Sasha joined the court with 20 years of experience as a partner at a national law firm, trial attorney, and mediator. While in private practice, she served extensively as a Judge Pro Tem, Settlement Conference Officer, and Mandatory Settlement Conference Panelist. She is an Adjunct Professor at USF School of Law and served on the UC Hastings Foundation Board of Trustees. Raised in Northern California&amp;rsquo;s Wine Country, Sasha earned her J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stephen M. Liacouras&lt;span style=&#39;font-weight: normal;&#39;&gt;, Chief Circuit Mediator&lt;/span&gt;</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/stephen-m-liacouras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/stephen-m-liacouras/</guid>
      <description>Stephen was selected as Chief Circuit Mediator in 2018, after having served as a Circuit Mediator for 17 years. Prior to joining the mediation office, he practiced civil litigation at small San Francisco firm, served as a Supervising Ninth Circuit Staff Attorney, and worked as an in-house attorney for a technology company in Austin, Texas. Stephen teaches a negotiation class as an Adjunct Professor at UC Hastings Law and is a volunteer panel mediator for the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steve Saltiel&lt;span style=&#39;font-weight: normal;&#39;&gt;, Circuit Mediator&lt;/span&gt;</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/steve-saltiel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/steve-saltiel/</guid>
      <description>Prior to joining the court in 2019, Steve was an Assistant United States Attorney in the U.S. Attorney&#39;s Office for the Northern District of California, serving at times as the Senior Litigation Counsel and Deputy Chief of the Civil Division. Steve is a volunteer panel mediator for the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of California. &amp;nbsp;Before moving to San Francisco in 1998, Steve was a partner at a small litigation boutique in New York City.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submit Confidential Information</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/addlconfinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/addlconfinfo/</guid>
      <description>United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit Submit Confidential Information Please complete this form to submit pertinent confidential information directly to the Circuit Mediators. Information submitted through this form will not appear on the docket and will be seen only by the Circuit Mediators.  Confidential submissions may include any information relevant to mediation of the case and settlement potential, including, but not limited to, settlement history, ongoing or potential settlement discussions, non-litigated party related issues, other pending actions, and timing considerations that may impact mediation efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test of Lambda Update</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/media_test3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/media_test3/</guid>
      <description>This is a test of the Lambda update functionality</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Mediating on Appeal</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/the-benefits-of-mediating-on-appeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/the-benefits-of-mediating-on-appeal/</guid>
      <description>Mediation at the appellate level provides just as many opportunities for resolution as mediating at the district court level. Indeed, many of the reasons to mediate at the trial court level still exist on appeal: time, expense, risk of loss, preservation of a relationship, a desire to make or avoid legal precedent, etc. An agreement crafted through mediation may prove a better remedy than what a court could fashion. The pause in the proceedings provided by the appeal can offer the parties an opportunity to reevaluate these interests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mediation Process</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/the-mediation-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/the-mediation-process/</guid>
      <description>The Ninth Circuit Mediation Program was established to facilitate settlement of cases on appeal pursuant to Federal Rule of Appellate Procedure 33 and Circuit Rule 33-1.  Participation in the Program  Almost all civil cases in which the parties are represented by counsel are eligible for the Mediation Program. The Mediation Questionnaire is the primary vehicle by which cases are directed to the program. Appellants are required to file the Mediation Questionnaire within seven days of the docketing of an appeal or a petition for review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ninth Circuit Mediators</title>
      <link>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/ninth-circuit-mediators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dy08pdae2ui3e.cloudfront.net/ca9/public/mediation/ninth-circuit-mediators/</guid>
      <description>The Ninth Circuit Mediation Office is led by Chief Circuit Mediator Stephen M. Liacouras and a team of seven Circuit Mediators who work exclusively for the court of appeals. The Circuit Mediators are all licensed attorneys who have an average of twenty-five years of combined government, private-law and mediation practice. They are all experienced and highly trained in appellate mediation, negotiation, and Ninth Circuit practice and procedure. The Circuit Mediators are generalists and cases are assigned to them across all subject matter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
